<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My super awesome blog</title>
    <description>blog</description>
    <link>http://chrbanks.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://chrbanks.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting A New Blog With Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a log of my experiences setting up a new blog with Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been reading blogs for a long time.  It’s a great way to learn and keep up with things.  I’ve also flirted with the idea of creating my own programming blog as a way to share information and improve my writing skills among other things.  At various points I would create accounts at free hosted blog sites, but I would never actually do anything with them, coming up with all sorts of excuses:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“What if I post something incredibly stupid?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“What if I put a lot of effort into this and no one cares?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I prefer online anonymity”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things like these have done nothing but prevent me from moving toward my goals. So recently I decided I was just going to push forward and start blogging.  Then it was time to figure out how I was going to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-i-chose-jekyll&quot;&gt;Why I Chose Jekyll&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked into several tools to build a blog with, but settled on three to look into deeper: WordPress, Ghost, and Jekyll.  I spent several days after work researching them and comparing.  WordPress seemed like a lot more than I really need at the moment.  Ghost was similar.  I really didn’t want to have to worry about databases, security, web hosting plans, etc. which led to me choosing Jekyll.  If there comes a point where Jekyll no longer meets my needs I’ll see about something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;installing-jekyll&quot;&gt;Installing Jekyll&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up a new blog was as simple as following the documentation’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/quickstart/&quot;&gt;Quick-start guide&lt;/a&gt;.  This generated the default blog files, and after running the server I was able to see the blog in action locally.  The next step was to put the blog on &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/using-jekyll-with-pages&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where I came across an issue.  Github pages doesn’t yet support Jekyll 2.0.3, but this is what I downloaded.  So for now I’m pushing the build output to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chrbanks/chrbanks.github.io&quot;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt;.  Once Github Pages is updated to support the newer version I’ll see about putting the source in the repository instead.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 06:46:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://chrbanks.github.io/jekyll/blog/2014/05/25/starting-a-new-blog-with-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chrbanks.github.io/jekyll/blog/2014/05/25/starting-a-new-blog-with-jekyll/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
